Andreas Frisch

Age 37, Danish

Knowledge Areas

Programming Python, Scala, Haskell, AngularJS, Swift, SQL, React

Development Git, Docker, Continuous Integration, AWS, Agile, Waterfall, Testing, Kubernetes, Kafka

Other Latex, Quality and Infomation Security Management Systems, GAMP 5, Audit Readiness

Work Experience

2023- Cloud Engineer, DFDS A/S, Copenhagen.

The Cloud Engineering Team at DFDS develops and maintains the kubernetes and kafka cluster(s) used for all cloud based production systems in DFDS. Access to these services and related tooling happens through a Developer Portal which is also developed and maintained by the Cloud Engineering Team.

Main learnings: Developer Platform Development, Stakeholder Management, React

2021-2023 **Senior Backend Developer**, *SiteImprove*, Copenhagen.

As part of the inhouse Crawler Team, I partook in automatic web page scraping and subsequent data formatting. My primary accomplishment in my time at SiteImprove was the migration of a legacy Perl code base into GoLang. Tasks often included maintenance and monitoring of kubernetes. The Crawler Team required a strong focus on runtime and data load optimization in order to live up to our promises to the customers.

Main learnings: AWS Cloud, Kubernetes, Kafka, Legacy Code Migration,

2020-2021 **Security and Software Lead**, *Studies&Me*, Copenhagen.

Overseeing development of both frontends and backends in Studies&Me with responsibility for delivering software on time, assisting in planning software deliveries, helping build the Studies&Me Quality and Information Security Management System, and managing day-to-day software security and operations. During this I still assisted in the development of our backend projects and maintained our supporting script suite.

Main learnings: People Management, Project Management, Politics, Quality Systems, Information Security, Audits.

2016–2020 **Software Developer**, *LEO Innovation Lab*, Copenhagen.

Part of the Core Services team developing common backend features for use in all the projects throughout the organisation.

Main learnings: Scala, AWS, Microservices, Project Management.

2014–2016 Consultant, Trifork, London.

Working primarily with American customers and on the internal project The Perfect App. *Main learnings: AngularJS, Project Management.*

2012–2014 **Junior Consultant**, *IT Minds*, Copenhagen.

Providing software solutions for customers such as Mærsk and Copenhagen University. *Main learnings: Customer relations, company politics.*

2011–2012 **IT Support**, *Copenhagen University*, Copenhagen.

General IT support as well as server maintenance, server acquisition, and daily operation. *Main learnings: Server maintenance, patience.*

2009–2010 **Developer**, *Copenhagen University*, Copenhagen.

Developing prototypes for the CITH and ESICT projects.

Main learnings: Customer relations, backend design, Django.

2008–2009 **Trainee Security Consultant**, *Digicure*, Kgs Lyngby.

Supporting senior consultants analysing network traffic and penetration test results.

Extracurricular Activities

2018- App Developer, GrocerEase, App Development and React Native.

Primary frontend developer for GrocerEase developing an app to help prevent food waste by allowing you to track food you have in your fridge and suggest new recipes using your leftovers.

2017- Board Game Guru, Bastard Cafe.

Volunteering to help people of all ages explore and enjoy board games.

2017–2018 **Teacher**, *Coding Pirates*.

Volunteering to teach kids aged 8 to 15 how to code. This was achieved primarily in Scratch but Javascript and Python also played a part.

2015–2016 **Teacher**, GOTO Academy Amsterdam, AngularJS.

While working for Trifork I taught several courses on AngularJS. Each course took four days – covering everything from HTML and simple bindings to interlinked components.

2010–2014 **Teacher's Assistant**, Copenhagen University, Functional Programming and Object Oriented Engineering.

Object Oriented Engineering had little to do with actual programming, focusing instead on all the softer aspects of delivering a successful software project such as requirement specification, planning, and documentation.

Education

- 2007–2014 **Bachelor and Masters Degree**, *Copenhagen University*, Copenhagen Denmark, *Computer Science*.
 - 2020 **Course**, Concept Heidelberg, Online, Computerized System Validation: The GAMP 5 Approach.

Languages

Danish Native

English Fluent

French Still trying

About me

I am a problem solver at heart and and seeing suboptimal solutions to problems which have better solutions immediately available easily distract me – or at worst annoys me. However, especially when considering programming problems I find it is important to not strife for perfection but rather consider continuous usefulness improvements. This balance is the crux of project management as I see it, and I enjoy being on either side of that discussion.

I love learning new tidbits of knowledge in many different fields. Whether picking up guitar chords or acquiring programming knowledge, the simple act of improving overall knowledge is fulfilling to me. This makes me less of a specialist and more of a jack-of-all-trades, but I consider that a strength in most situations when interacting with different people from different fields.

I enjoy people and spend quite a lot of time socialising – preferably over board games with a gin and tonic in hand.